Hi, I'm John Kiriakou. And welcome back
to another episode of deep focus Q&A. So
first, as always, I want to thank each
and every one of you deeply for
continuing to watch the show, to like,
to subscribe, to to refer your friends
and family members to it. We keep
growing and we're growing only because
of you. So thank you so much. Please
keep it up. We've got a ton of questions
today, which of course I love. And the
first one is from Noah R. Lyons. He
says, "Hi John, are you a Pens fan?"
Meaning the Pittsburgh Penguins.
Absolutely yes, I'm a Pens fan. I'm not
even a huge like hockey fan, not as big
of a hockey fan as I am baseball and
football, but you got to love the Pens.
I still remember when I was 14 years
old, Pittsburgh was the the city of
champions. We won the Super Bowl, the
World Series, and the Stanley Cup all in
the same year.
God bless Pittsburgh. So Noah says, "My
question is about the Strait of Hormuz.
Since Iran's ceasefire terms require
ships to coordinate passage with their
military, and their proposal apparently
includes formal control over the strait
going forward, does that represent a
permanent change from how it worked
before the war? And if they're allowed
to charge transit fees as part of a
final deal, how much of that cost do you
foresee getting passed on through oil,
fertilizer, and other commodities?
Thanks for everything. Much love and
fingers crossed for your pardon. Thank
you."
Uh
really important questions. And the
truth is that that the facts on the
ground are changing literally daily.
Since Noah wrote this question, um the
Iranians have said that uh
that they would charge a fee for each
ship going through. The fee has been as
high as $2 million per ship, payable in
yuan, not in dollars,
which is going to be a direct challenge
to uh US uh you know, economic uh
control of the of the region or of of
the oil going through the region. Um but
just a couple of days ago Donald Trump
said that the US would would take over
the strait. Today is day two. We're
recording this on Monday morning, and
the US Navy said this morning that they
indeed have control of the strait, and
the strait is again closed. We're living
in bizarro world here, where US policy
has always been that the strait has to
remain open.
And now it's the US that is ensuring
that the strait remains closed.
So, like I say, it's the twilight zone,
and we're going to have to try to figure
this out one day at a time.
So, does this represent a permanent
change from how it worked before the
war? Yeah, absolutely.
The The status quo before the war was
that, you know, the strait is very, very
narrow. It's only 16 mi at its narrowest
point, and
ships like have to barely be on the
international side of the
of the line of Iranian um territorial
waters. So, if the IRGC and its fast
boats, the Iran Revolutionary Guard
Corps and its fast boats, are out there
harassing ships, well, of course, that's
unacceptable. If the US Navy is there
blockading the strait, that is also
unacceptable. And so,
my my own belief is, in the end,
there aren't going to be any fees. There
isn't going to be an American blockade,
and the Iranians are going to go back to
their side of the of the uh of their
territorial waters. It's going to take
some time, though, because of ongoing
hostilities.
Um, another thing to keep in mind,
65%
of the world's fertilizer
goes through the Strait of Hormuz.
65%
The The can't eat without fertilizer.
And God knows Ukraine can't
provide enough enough
wheat.
You know, Ukraine is the world's
breadbasket, they call it. They can't
provide enough wheat without any
fertilizer
to feed all of Africa. And right now
Ukraine feeds all of Africa.
So, this is an untenable position. It's
it can't last.
Uh people are going to starve to death.
And so,
the two sides are going to have to come
to some sort of an agreement, even if
it's a temporary one,
to allow
on the one hand fertilizer and oil to
get through the strait, and on the other
hand for the Iranians to
make something out of it. And it's not
going to be in dollars.
Nick W
says, "Hi John, I discovered you a
couple of weeks ago and I'm a big fan
already. Thank you, Nick.
My question is, what's your view on bias
in US mainstream media, cable news, and
papers?
I can't help but to smile because bias
is like ridiculous. And where do you go
to do your own research?
Um how do you know if a source is
trustworthy? Thanks and keep up the good
work. I hope my small donation makes a
difference." And thank you for that,
Nick.
Um yeah, I I believe that the mainstream
media is biased
even if they don't even realize that
they're biased. And I'll give you one
egregious example from last week. There
was a front page photograph on the
Washington Post of of a dud Iranian
missile laying
in the playground of a school.
And the the caption said, you know,
"Israeli children
walking past an Iranian missile on the
playground of their school." Yeah.
So, where's your picture of the Iranian
school that was actually blown up by the
American missile and killed what was it?
270, you know, 9, 10, 11, and
12-year-olds.
Why are we only getting the one side of
this conflict? Why Why isn't the
mainstream media saying that the
president's threat to destroy Iranian
infrastructure is a war crime? Because
it's the definition of a war crime. You
cannot attack civilian infrastructure.
It is against the law.
But the mainstream media aren't talking
about that.
And I mean, they're all guilty. The New
York Times, The Washington Post, CNN, MS
Now, Fox, they're all guilty. I will say
The Associated Press is generally okay.
And Reuters is is pretty good. So, you
ask what I read in the morning. I'm
going to read it off to you.
And I I'm I'm telling you what I read
every morning, not what I believe every
morning. I read when I get up The
Washington Post, The Wall Street
Journal, The New York Times, The Los
Angeles Times,
The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette just for the
sports, and they're going out of
business in a couple of weeks. CNN, AP,
Politico, The Hill, The New York Post
just because they're just so awful. You
have to know what the other side's
saying.
Uh the Greek papers, which you're not
interested in. Uh The Telegraph, The
Times of London, The Guardian, The
London Evening Standard, BBC, Dropsite
News,
Al Jazeera, Al Monitor, Electronic
Intifada, Consortium News, Real Clear
Politics, Axios.
And then I take a quick look at Covert
Action Magazine, although I write for
Covert Action Magazine, and we don't
update it uh every day. It's usually
updated every couple of days.
And then I look at at things like,
you know, the stuff that's
unusual. Like if there's if there's a an
especially good
uh
article in the Miami Herald about
Venezuela for example or Cuba,
I don't have a subscription there, but
I'll I'll buy, you know, the one-time
article.
Also, I try I try to spend as much time
on Twitter as I can just because
I don't follow a ton of people, but the
people I do follow are people whose
reporting I respect.
Uh Ryan Grim for example or Max
Blumenthal or
um
Oh my gosh, there's so many. Elizabeth
Lane, uh
so many of them. Anyway, they're out
there looking for
truth in reporting and when they post
things, I always check it out, too. The
The bottom line is you can't just rely
on one or two or 10 sources. You have to
You have to find people who have been
proven correct in their reporting, who
have been proven diligent in their
reporting. Follow them and then let them
do the heavy lifting so you don't have
to search every every outlet in the
world.
Thanks for that good question.
Eoin O'Reilly.
Irish names. I I just
I apologize if I butchered it.
Um Hey John, as an 18-year-old from
Ireland, what intelligence opportunities
are there for people from countries of
non-major international importance? As a
European, do you see a possible European
army if NATO collapses and who will
Europe turn to for friendship with US
being an utter hindrance to us now?
Thank you so much for your work. I know
a classmate of mine met you in Poland.
Oh, that's funny.
Yeah, I was in Poland a couple of weeks
ago. Couldn't be more jealous. Thank you
for that. Hopefully one day I'll have
the pleasure of shaking your hand. Thank
you for that. I was in Ireland Monday,
Tuesday, and Wednesday, so I'm sorry I
missed you. Sending the luck of the
Irish for your apartment and pension.
Thank you so much.
Great questions. Number one, Donald
Trump cannot withdraw from NATO. I think
nobody has told him yet that only
Congress can withdraw from NATO. So, the
United States isn't going anywhere out
of NATO. So, he's going to have to get
that out of his head. Just like the
president cannot change the name of the
Department of Defense to the Department
of War. Only Congress can change the
name.
So, it's not the Department of War, it's
the Department of Defense. So, number
two,
our leader has embarrassed our country
when it comes to our relations with our
European friends and allies.
There's just no other way to say it. I'm
sorry, but
this has been an utter embarrassment.
These threats against NATO are
counterproductive. They don't do
anything. The US isn't pulling out of
NATO. Nothing's going to happen in NATO.
He can yell and scream all he wants and
nothing's going to change.
So, do I see a possible European army if
NATO collapses? In the unlikely event
that NATO collapsed, absolutely, yes.
There would be a European Union army,
which would essentially be, you know,
NATO plus five or six. So, yeah, I I
would see that absolutely taking place.
You ask also if there are opportunities,
intelligence opportunities for people
from the smaller
European countries. 100% yes. I gave a
series of speeches around I Ireland a
little more than a year ago. I went to
Belfast, Cork, Dublin, and Waterford
before going on to um
Scotland. And
I met with a lot of European
intelligence and law enforcement
officials. Listen, if there's one thing
that that the Irish are especially good
at,
it's anti-money laundering
investigations. The Irish intelligence
service and the Irish
Garda
are first class when it comes to
anti-money laundering. But, another
thing that they're good at is
counterterrorism. And the reason they're
so good at counterterrorism is because
there were so many Irish
going to Libya and Lebanon in the 1970s
to be trained by Carlos the Jackal, who
was, you know, the Osama bin Laden of
the '70s and '80s. And so, the Irish
government just got really, really good
at recruiting spies to penetrate these
various groups, Irish groups mostly, in
in many cases,
you know, Northern Irish or sort of
international communist that were in
league with the Popular Front for the
Liberation of Palestine, the Democratic
Front for the Liberation of Palestine,
the Abu Nidal Organization, Carlos the
Jackal, the Libyans.
And they've maintained that expertise.
So, if you're interested in
intelligence, look no further than the
Irish government. They're really good.
Uh
Dr. Vamps says, "Hi, John. I wish you
the best in getting that pardon. Thank
you."
"What specific tells did you rely on the
most when assessing if a high-value
target was telling the truth? Was it all
body language or also some verbal tells?
I'd also love to hear a story regarding
this. Have a great day. Keep up the good
work." I've got a story for you, one
that I've never told publicly. Maybe I
should start telling it publicly. First
of all, the the tells the the verbal
tells are the obvious ones, where you
ask them a question and then they kind
of look down
before they answer you, or they look up
as if they're visualizing something.
Yeah, you know, I'm right here. Look me
in the eye when you talk to me. Don't
look up and around and down and this
way. Straight in the eye. That was kind
kind the obvious tell. Also, the
fidgeting. The fidgeting is a is a big
tell. The arms crossing. Arms crossing
means that you're you're nervous and
defensive. A lot of people do that.
Frankly, I cross my arms cuz I just like
the way it feels. But, um
but those were some of the obvious
tells.
How you get past all that, how you get
around it is this. You go into
a debriefing or an interrogation.
Interrogation is the word that the FBI
uses. The CIA doesn't interrogate, it
interviews or debriefs.
Um
don't pay any attention to that. That's
just CIA silliness. But, anyway, what
what we were trained to do was to go in
to these interviews already knowing the
answers to all of our questions. Now,
that's a that's a basic, you know,
police detective tactic.
But, uh we we captured
a high-value target who had flown into
Pakistan.
We knew for days in advance that he had
bought a ticket in his own name, like a
He he uses his own credit card, buys a
ticket in his true name, one-way ticket
to Pakistan, and we had six guys waiting
for him at the airport. So, we grab him,
and they send him to me in Islamabad.
And I knew exactly who he was. I knew
exactly who he had been meeting with in
the country that he came from.
I knew that he was
mid-to-high-level Al-Qaeda. He was not
some, you know, street fighter. This was
a serious guy, a dangerous guy, a guy
that had, literally, American blood on
his hands.
And, um
and so, we had him handcuffed, and the
cuffs are are connected to a uh they're
they're chained to an eye bolt that had
been
uh screwed into the table.
So, I asked him his name.
And he pretends to have severe stomach
pain. And he's like doubled over in
pain. Oh my god. Well,
I've read the Al-Qaeda training manual,
right? We captured an original copy of
the Al-Qaeda training manual. And this
is number one.
Literally, it's number one. Pretend to
have severe stomach pain and fall off
the chair. So, he fell off the chair
with his hand still chained to the
table. And I just sat there in the
chair. He opens one eye and looks up to
me. And I said, "I read the training
manual.
Get back in the chair."
So, then he gets back up. He sits in the
chair.
I said, "What's your name?" He's like,
"Mohammed Abdallah." I said, "Eh, try
again. What's your name?"
He came up with some other name. Wrong
second time. You're going to really piss
me off if you give me a third fake name.
Then he gave me his real name.
And then we just kind of took it from
there. But he tried everything. He
pretended to faint. He did the whole
stomach thing. Uh he pretended that he
was going to throw up like
And I just kind of sat there like this
looking at him like, "Are you done?
I read the training manual.
Um
he lied. Everything that that he told us
was a lie.
And then
I told him, "Listen,
I'm I'm the good cop in this.
We can either have a conversation like
two grown men
or, you know, we're going to we're going
to send you someplace that you're not
going to like."
And he's like, "I'm not afraid of
Guantanamo." I said, "Guantanamo?
I never said I was going to send you to
Guantanamo.
I'm going to send you to Jerusalem."
Now, of course, I would never send him
to Jerusalem. We don't do that. We send
them to way worse places than Jerusalem.
That scared the out of him.
And then he just started talking.
And he gave us everything.
And then he went to Guantanamo. I don't
even know whatever happened to him. He's
probably still there.
But anyway,
yeah, body language is a big deal, but
but you've got to know the answers to
your questions
before you even go into the meeting.
Before our next question,
I wanted to say, uh I wanted to give you
a word from one of our sponsors. Last
week the Treasury put out its financial
report for 2025, and almost no one
covered it.
Here's what it said. $6 trillion in
assets, $47 trillion in debt. The US
government is $41 trillion in net debt.
That's not my opinion. That's the
Treasury Department's own numbers. A few
days ago, Fed Chairman Jerome Powell
said that the death path that the debt
path will not end well. You can say that
again. Those were his actual words.
Meanwhile, the big beautiful bill added
$3 trillion more in debt.
And now we're paying more than $1
trillion a year just in interest on the
debt. Well, I spent more than 14 years
in the CIA. I learned to spot problems
before they blew up. Right now, central
banks all over the world are buying gold
as fast as they can. China, Poland,
India, they see what's coming.
I've put together a free report along
with American Alternative Assets called
the Big Beautiful Bubble. It shows
what's really going on and how to
protect your savings before this thing
gets worse. So, go to johnlovesgold.com
for your free copy. That's
johnlovesgold.com
or call 888-GOLD-053.
Travis Veaner says, "Hello, John. Hope
you're doing well. I have some questions
for your next show. Would it be
appropriate to call this Iran war a
rogue action by the Trump
administration? It doesn't appear to
have the blessings of the deep state and
it is constantly counter-signaled in our
media and by our allies or am I off the
mark?
Also, are there levers for intelligence
agencies to pull to prime the public? I
see you, Tucker Carlson, Joe Kent, and
others all have huge pushes in the
algorithm, especially your anti-Israel
content. Could the deep state be priming
the American people to leave Israel
holding the bag? I believe that is what
does what's deserved."
Good questions. Um first, would it be
appropriate to call this Iran war a
rogue action by the Trump
administration? Yes.
Yes, there's been no congressional
declaration of war.
There has been no congressional
authorization for the use of force,
which is a, you know, limp-wristed way
of declaring war without actually
declaring it.
And there is no
there has been no vote by the United
Nations Security Council. Listen,
international law allows you to attack
another country for three reasons.
Number one, they've attacked you.
Right?
Number two, they have asked you to come
in and attack in order to save them.
And number three, the United Nations
Security Council authorized a use of
military force. None of those three
things have happened.
We just attacked because the Israelis
asked us to. That's it. That's an
illegal war. It's a violation of
international law and in fact, it's
it's quite literally a war crime,
something that I've been saying from the
very beginning.
You are correct, Travis, that
this action does not
appear to have had the
support, the blessings of the deep
state. Uh in fact, when we attacked Iraq
in 2003, the battle lines were clearly
drawn right down the middle in the US
government. The pro-war factions were
the Office of the Vice President, OVP,
the Office of the Secretary of Defense,
OSD, and the National Security Council.
And the anti-war factions were CIA,
State, and the Joint Chiefs. Well, we
know, thanks to leaks, that this Iran
war
has not had the support of the ODNI, the
Office of the Director of National
Intelligence, and consequently the CIA,
the Office of the Vice President, and
the Joint Chiefs.
But,
the White House, the NSC, the State
Department,
that's all been the pro-war faction.
Um you are not off the mark.
It is constantly counter-signaled in the
media. And it's funny to see Fox News
just beating itself up over this,
because on the one hand,
you know, they bought into the whole
MAGA no foreign wars thing,
but now you've got Hannity who's a
cheerleader for the war.
I'm going on his show day after
tomorrow, and I think he and I are
probably going to go to the mat over
this.
Uh
you've got uh Jesse Waters who like
wasn't sure what to do, and then came
down on the side of the war. And then
other Fox hosts that are that are
anti-war.
And then you've got,
you know, MSNBC, like really loving the
idea of the war because it's, you know,
for Israel, but then hating the idea
that the war is being prosecuted by
Donald Trump. So, they're confused, too.
And then CNN is like, well, you know,
we're trying to be
not biased, but we kind of like the war
because we like Israel, but we don't
like Donald Trump, so we're going to
kind of be against the war. They don't
know what to do.
They're just kind of stuck. You make a
very interesting point here
that
there could be levers for the
intelligence community to
prime the pump.
You say, I see you Tucker Carlson, Joe
Kent, and others. I'm going to add uh
uh
well, yeah, others uh being pushed in
the algorithm.
I
I I have no explanation for it, but I I
have to I have to agree with you. My
algorithm is Tucker, Tucker, Tucker,
Candace Owens, me,
Kent, Tucker, Tucker, Candace Owens.
And it's all pretty much the same
message. And you may be onto something
here about the deep state having some
kind of effect on on the algorithm.
In which case I welcome it.
I welcome it.
Uh Lance says, "Hi John, I have been a
fan for about a year now. Thank you,
Lance. I believe you're an American hero
and I hope you get your well-deserved
pardon. Thank you for that. I am an
incoming journalism major and wonder if
you could talk about how journalists,
specifically investigative ones, are
persecuted by intelligence agencies
across the world. I'm very passionate
about this subject because I wish to
become an investigative journalist
myself one day. You are truly an
inspiration to me and if you ever ran
for president, thank you. You have my
vote." I appreciate that. "God bless,
John. You have no idea how much of an
impact you've had on young men like
myself." Thank you very, very much,
Lance. And you know, it's funny. No, I
I I do have no idea. It's only like in
the last couple of weeks
that my life has gone crazy. I mean,
quite seriously, I can't go 10 ft down
the street without somebody asking me
for a selfie and I always always say
yes.
Always. I was telling Chris, our our uh
producer and sound engineer,
I went to a baseball game a week ago
yesterday
and
15 separate times people came to my seat
during the game and asked me to take a
selfie.
I always say yes.
I was in Ireland Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday
to accept the gold medal for
uh
uh integrity in
the public discourse. Thank you very
much to Trinity College. Um
I took 500 selfies the first day. 500 it
took 3 and 1/2 hours. The line went like
around the block.
And uh and then another 60 after dinner
just walking from the restaurant to uh
to my hotel. I was in Berlin the week
before filming a documentary and we were
filming out on the street and were
interrupted 35 times
by people asking for selfies. I went to
Poland for the day just cuz I'd never
been to Poland before and I wanted to
say I ate pierogies in in Poland.
And I got stopped in Poland
for selfies
by people that don't even speak English.
So
something happened to the algorithm. I
don't know what it is. I am
extraordinarily grateful for it.
Um
but it's only now that I'm beginning to
understand that that people in the like
15 to 30
age group
almost exclusively men
um are listening to me.
So thank you very much for that. Now
getting to this investigative journalism
thing
there are very few
professions in my humble view
that are more important than
investigative journalists.
Um
and what we're seeing right now is the
death of investigative journalism in the
mainstream media. Joby Warrick
is a friend of mine, a long-time
investigative journalist for the
Washington Post. This is the kind of guy
who is on the level of Woodward and
Bernstein.
Multiple Pulitzer Prize winner. You can
bet your bottom dollar that whatever Joe
B. writes is the truth.
And he resigned 2 weeks ago because
investigative journalism at the
Washington Post is dead. This is This is
the newspaper of record
that brought down a president
with the Watergate investigation.
And it's done.
Jeff Bezos killed it. Did you know that
since Jeff Bezos bought the Washington
Post 80%
of the employees at the Washington Post
have been let go?
80%
Now, the real investigative journalism
is being done by outlets like
ProPublica. Go to propublica.com
or .org or whatever it is. They're
amazing. Go to the Brennan Center.
Amazing investigative reporting.
Dropsite News.
Uh Max Blumenthal at The Grayzone. I
mean, this is real investigative
journalism. So, it's still being done.
It's just not necessarily being done at
the the Post, the New York Times, the
Wall Street Journal, the LA Times, the
places where it used to be done.
And think of this, too.
You're not going to get rich
being investigative being an
investigative journalist. But getting
rich should not be your goal. Seeking
the truth should be your goal. So, I say
go for it. Go to the best school you can
get into. By God, if you can get into
Columbia School of Journalism, go to
Columbia. If you can't, just go to the
best school you can get into.
Practice, practice, practice, even if
it's just at the school paper or for
outlets like Consortium News or The Gray
Zone or
Covert Action Magazine or
Reader-Supported News,
get published as much as you can,
and then set your sights on the big
time. Very best of luck. I think what
you're doing is very admirable.
Nessam Camel says, "Hey John, I'm not
sure if you've answered this question
before, but do you know about What do
you know about UAPs? I think I heard you
had a sighting yourself." I did.
And also have seen dancing lights in the
sky.
Or you have seen dancing lights in the
sky. It's something that's completely
dumbfounded me, and I was wondering if
you knew any more than than I. Seems
like they're able to defy the laws of
physics as we know them and inhabit
airspace and sea. Cheers for the amazing
work. Hope you get your pardon. Thank
you. You know, I've I've told the story
before, but I'll tell it again.
Um
I was 17 years old,
and my mom and dad owned a restaurant in
the next town to the north. We lived in
New Castle, Pennsylvania, and they owned
a restaurant in Sharon, Pennsylvania.
So, Sharon was 15 mi north, and to get
there, you had to go through Amish
country. And the Amish don't use
electricity, so it's very very dark
there.
My dad and I used to work together on uh
midnight shift Friday nights and
Saturday nights. And so, we would leave
home at uh at 10:00. We'd get to Sharon
around 10:20 and start our shift at
11:00. It was an 11:00 to 7:00 shift.
And so, we're driving through Amish
country, and we see this blinding flash
of white light.
Not high off the ground. I'm going to
say 1,200 to 1,500 ft off the ground.
And then there's a second flash, and
then a third flash, like blinding.
And then this orange
trapezoid lights up
in the shape of a saucer
and it has these glowing orange lights
in the four at the four angles of the
saucer.
And it's just hovering there.
I said, "What is that?"
My dad pulls the car over to the side of
the highway. We get out of the car and
we're just standing there like looking
at it. Like, "What What is that?"
And this guy pulls up behind us. He gets
out of his car and he says, "What is
that?" And my dad said, "I don't know."
And then it just went
at this fantastic speed
that just defied the laws of physics.
It didn't make any sound at all.
And we stood there for a good minute
afterwards just looking up into the sky
thinking, "Is it going to come back?
Like, is it going to land?" We couldn't
see it anymore.
And then finally we just got in the car
and drove the rest of the way to the the
restaurant. And I said to my dad during
the drive, I said, "Should we call
somebody? Like, should we call the
cops?"
I was 17. And he said, "And tell them
what?
We saw a flying saucer and it flew away?
They'll think we're nuts."
And so we didn't tell anybody. We told
my mom the next day and then that was
it.
Years later, I mentioned this to my
cousin
here in the Washington area. My cousin
was an F-15 fighter pilot.
And I said,
"Cuz,
we saw the craziest thing one time. I'm
talking this is, you know,
45 years ago.
And um and I told him what I just told
you. And he said, "Oh." He goes, "That
That's nothing."
He said, "We used to see these things
all the time." He said, "One time I was
off the coast of uh Norfolk, Virginia
and I saw one come out of the water."
Out of the water.
in the ocean.
And they they fly at these fantastic
speeds, they make turns, and they sort
of cut at angles that
that the laws of physics tell us are not
possible.
But they've all seen them. He said, you
have to file a classified report. It
goes to the Pentagon, and then it's just
gets lost in the black hole there.
On my very first day at the CIA,
literally my very first question of my
new boss was,
where are the UFOs?
And he laughed and he said,
that that's the first question for all
of us on our first day. And I'll tell
you what my boss told me and his boss
told him.
All that information is at the Pentagon.
None of it's here. We don't have any
idea what those things are.
So, there you have it.
Philosopher Vale says, "Hi John, new fan
here." Oh, welcome.
From your recent mega viral wave. I
know, right?
20-year-old fan who has always had an
interest in how the CIA and other spy
agencies work. Won't lie and say I'm an
old fan. I do have a few questions.
Number one.
What are your thoughts or inquiries on
the recent CIA operations this year? For
example, the insertion of agents into
Venezuela prior to the Maduro raid, the
use of the ghost murmur device in Iran
to rescue the downed F-15 pilot, and the
CIA attempts to inspire a Kurdish
rebellion in Iran.
All excellent questions. I'll get to
them in a second.
Number two. On your Instagram videos,
what do you think of commentators
accusing you of still working for the
CIA as some sort of recruitment tool to
make the CIA sound cool? You know what?
Let me answer that one right now. I
think that they're brain
damaged. Number one. There's literally
nothing that's more intellectually lazy
than saying, "Once CIA, always CIA."
Like, are you deranged? If you
think I went to prison
to make the CIA look sexy,
then you've got some serious mental and
emotional problems.
So, no, I dismiss those people as
unserious and unworthy of a response.
And number three, what is your
experience with the intelligence
agencies of small less important nations
on the global stage? Great question. I
mean, really small countries like
Jamaica or Fiji or Bolivia or random
sub-Saharan African nations.
That's a great question. Nobody's ever
asked me that question before.
You know what? Let me answer that one
first because uh it's easy and quick and
then we'll get to your first one, which
is more complicated.
Um
I went to the
I went to the Djibouti intelligence
service one time.
I'm not exaggerating when I tell you
that this very humble rental townhouse
that I live in
was twice the size of the Djibouti
intelligence service.
Um my humble little living room here,
which has room for a couch, a chair, a
coffee table, and a TV, I'm looking at
it,
was twice the size of the office of the
director of the Djibouti intelligence
service.
Most of these little countries, and I've
I've I've dealt with a lot of the little
countries. And you And when you go and
you treat them with respect, you call
the director your Excellency or Mr.
Director or General and what an honor it
is, I'm humbled to be here to visit your
intelligence service, we so look forward
to working together. You do all the
right things diplomatically. Um but for
the most part, those intelligence
services, they just do what you ask them
to do.
It's as simple as that. And they know
that you're going to you're going to do
right by them. They'll call and say,
"Hey, listen, we we really need like
20 pairs of night vision goggles and we
we can't afford them. And we're not
talking about the Teemu ones that are
100 bucks. We're talking about real ones
that are like 1,500 bucks.
And then you say, "How many do you
need?" Uh 20 pairs. All right, not a
problem. We'll have them shipped over.
That's what you do.
And so, relations remain good that way.
Yeah. I always enjoyed working with
those those little agencies. Your first
question is a very good one and very
complicated. What are my thoughts on the
recent CIA operations this year, the
insertion of agents in Venezuela
prior to the Maduro raid? Um
that's aggressive, but that is what the
CIA does.
That would have been done by something
called the Special Activities Division.
The Special Activities Division is made
up almost exclusively of
of
military special forces, Navy SEALs,
Delta Force, Army Rangers, all the
special forces guys on loan from the
Pentagon to the CIA, usually for
individual operations.
Right? So, it's a CIA operation,
but it's carried out by special forces
on loan to the CIA.
I am almost 100% sure that was the case
in the Maduro raid.
The use of the Ghost Whisperer device.
Wow. I've talked to several CIA friends
about Ghost Whisperer. If you don't know
what Ghost Whisperer is, you know, we
lost uh this F-15 in Iran a week ago or
so, and one of the pilots was rescued
quickly. The other pilot had to hide. He
actually held he actually um hid in a
crevice between two rocks.
So, the Pentagon did one thing while the
CIA was doing another. The Pentagon
created a diversion using another F-15
and an A-10 Warthog that was about 50 mi
away from where the pilot was to draw
the Iranian forces away from the pilot's
location.
And the Warthog was all shot up.
Warthogs fly very slowly and they bomb
the crap out of things. Mostly
they're mostly used for anti-armor
operations, attacking tanks and armored
personnel carriers. Very, very cool
planes. By far the favorite plane of the
Pentagon and they were discontinued
recently and there was such an uproar
that they brought them back. So, 50
miles away the A-10 is shooting at the
ground and the ground is shooting at the
A-10 and and then the F-15 is screaming
by and they're shooting at the F-15 cuz
they're they're diverting attention.
Ghost murmur is this new technology
that was on a drone
being controlled
by the CIA from CIA headquarters.
And if the reporting is to be believed
the drone had technology on it that
could hear the pilot's heartbeat from 40
miles away. I said to my friends, I said
that can't
possibly be the case.
Like that's some Star Trek right
there.
They maintained that it was true. I'm
going to say it was an exaggeration, but
either way they knew exactly where that
pilot was because they could detect the
heartbeat whether it was from, you know,
40 miles or 4 miles or
I don't know, 40 40 feet. I don't know.
But they could detect his his heartbeat
and they were able to pinpoint his exact
location hidden in a crevice between two
rocks to successfully rescue him.
The CIA attempts to inspire a Kurdish
rebellion. Yeah, that's another stupid
idea that has CIA written all over it.
We did the same thing with the Iraqi
Kurds. We did the same thing with the
Syrian Kurds. You just
you just airdrop shipments of weapons
and and hope they, you know, start
shooting Iranian military or IRGC or
Quds Force or whatever. Instead, they
started shooting each other and shooting
Iraqi Kurds and, you know,
that stuff never works. That was just a
dumb idea. But the yeah, that's that's a
very typical,
you know, low-cost,
low blowback potential CIA operation.
Thank you,
Philosopher Veil, for those outstanding
questions. I want to give you a word
from our second sponsor, too. If there's
one thing that we've learned over the
last few years, it is that access to
medication can change quickly depending
on politics, regulation, and corporate
influence. That is why it's important to
have a pharmacy that focuses on access
and transparency, not on bureaucracy.
This is the reason why people are
turning to All Family Pharmacy. Instead
of scheduling doctor visits, sitting in
waiting rooms, and dealing with
insurance approvals, the entire process
is handled online. You choose the
medications you need on their website,
you fill out a short medical form, and a
licensed doctor reviews your request. If
appropriate, they provide the
prescription, then your order ships
directly to your door. It's a simple way
to keep essential medications on hand
like antibiotics, antivirals,
ivermectin, albendazole, NAD+ and more
than 400 other prescription medications
that people rely on every day. So,
prepare now before you need it in the
future. Visit
allfamilypharmacy.com/john,
j o h n, and use the promo code John10,
j o h n 1 0, to save 10% on your next
order. And I can tell you,
I've done this for an asthma inhaler and
um
oh, and a Z-Pak.
You never know when you're going to get
a sinus infection, especially in allergy
season. So, good to have a Z-Pak on hand
so you don't have to go to the urgent
care and spend $60 unnecessarily.
A question from our Spotify audience,
from Gast Man.
John, I am part of Gen Z and I feel
quite helpless uh when it comes to the
state of the world. What advice do you
have for the younger generation?
What actions should we take? What
careers should we go into?
Yeah, that's a tough one. I have to tell
you
I've said a thousand times, I'm 61 years
old. My earliest memories
Among my earliest memories are sitting
on my dad's lap and watching the news
and asking him why all these buildings
were on fire. And he told me that a very
bad man killed Martin Luther King and
that people were very angry. And then a
couple months later, my mother was
crying
and she told me that Robert Kennedy had
been killed. That a bad man shot Robert
Kennedy.
1968 was nightmarish.
It got worse in '69 with the Kent State
shootings. So, we've been through
periods of helplessness before.
World War II had to be just one
nightmare year after another.
I can only imagine what 1861 to 1865 was
like.
So, we've been through this before.
I I get how you feel. Some days I wake
up and I read the headlines and I feel
helpless, too. But, we're not helpless.
It is such a cliché to say that your
generation is the next generation of
leaders, but clichés are clichés because
they're true.
You're the next leaders.
And so, you've got to grab the bull by
the horns.
Run for office.
Any office. Run for the local water
board because then that's going to get
you elected next time to city council
and then to state legislature and then
to Congress. I mean, how do you think
these these people started? They started
at the bottom. You don't start by
running for the Senate in most cases.
You run for something else and then, you
know, finally we can elect people that
we can believe in that are going to that
are going to do what's best for the
country instead of what's best for for
themselves or lining their own pockets.
Get out there and demonstrate. I have a
friend and former colleague Brian Becker
who's the the founder of something
called the Answer Coalition.
Brian
has never cared about money.
He only cares about truth and activism
and equality.
And
he, just as one example,
he organized a demonstration just after
the October 7th attacks
when the Israelis started pounding
Palestinian civilians. He organized a
demonstration in Washington, D.C. And on
his application for a demonstration
permit at the Department of the
Interior, he said that he expected 25 to
30,000 people. I went to that
demonstration.
300,000
people turned up and the line stretched
from the White House to the Capitol
Building.
Now, that's a demonstration. We've got
to take to the streets.
We also have to ride our elected
officials.
And if they don't do what we tell them
to do, remember they work for us. If
they don't do what we tell them to do,
then they have to go and we have to vote
them out and bring somebody new in who
is going to do what we want them to do
or her to do and is going to represent
the people who put them in office.
At the same time, you have to write,
write, write. Place op-eds and articles
everywhere, whether it's in the big
mainstream papers if you have access to
them, or online publications. I've
recommended repeatedly Consortium News,
Covert Action Magazine, Reader Supported
News, Dropsite News. There are million
outlets out there. antiwar.com, the
American Conservative magazine.com.
There are million outlets.
Get your ideas out there and help to to
mold minds.
And then just stay as well informed as
you possibly can. The future really is
yours. And like I say, grab it by the
horns.
Rhetorical answer says,
"Hi John, what are some upcoming things
you're excited about in your life
recently? Secondly, I'm a Coptic
Orthodox Egyptian. All right. And was
wondering what you know about the
history and relations between the
Egyptians and the Greeks. As Egyptians
love making your food. For years I was
under the impression that my two
favorite foods
that my mother would cook cook were
Egyptian dishes, and it turned out that
they were Greek, dolmades and pastitsio.
Uh thank you for all your hard work. I
hope you give yourself the opportunity
for some rest now and then. PS, if you
ever find yourself in the New Jersey or
Philadelphia area and need a ride
anywhere, I'm a five-star Lyft Uber
driver,
and it would be my honor to drive you
wherever you want to go, free of charge.
Thank you so much. Christos Anesti.
Alithos Anesti, my friend.
Um thank you for that.
I I'm going to I'm going to
show a little bit of vulnerability here,
and I'm going to tell you that I have
struggled with depression my entire life
until recently.
The last
the last year has been especially good.
And
I haven't been this happy
in 20 years.
Things have really started to turn
around.
Um
personally, professionally, things are
going places. I'm optimistic about the
coming years.
Uh I hope I can stay healthy and enjoy
these new changes, but I'm I'm really
optimistic about things.
Um what I'm looking forward to, what I'm
excited about is
I have a lot of travel coming up, and I
think that there's probably nothing that
I love more in life than travel.
I'm going to go to Greece in June
and again in August.
I'm going to Egypt uh in August with my
son, and I'll get to that in a minute.
I'm going to go to Vietnam with my
brother-in-law
also in August.
Uh
I just got back
I was in Ireland week ago. I was in
Germany and Poland the week before.
Uh
I have a trip to Australia coming up. I
love travel more than anything else in
the world.
Um
Egypt.
I've been to Egypt many, many times, and
I have a deep love of Egypt.
And I know Cairo's got problems.
The the pollution, the air pollution
will choke the life right out of you.
It's ridiculous. The traffic is of epic
proportions, unparalleled practically
anywhere in the world, but it's Egypt.
It's a 5,000-year-old
civilization. You know, my son told me
just yesterday
Cleopatra
is closer in time to the iPhone
than she was to the pyramids.
That's how old the pyramids are.
So, I'm taking him to Cairo. We've been
talking about Egypt, Egypt, Egypt for
years, and finally I said, "Buddy, let's
just We're going to go to Greece in in
the in August in the summer. Let's just
go to Egypt, too. We'll take 4 days.
We'll see the the pyramids, the Sphinx.
We'll go to ancient Memphis. We'll go to
the new like A-list world-class
archaeological museum. I'm told it's
literally the best in the world. We're
going to go to Khan el-Khalili, the
souk, and go shopping like crazy people.
And then we've got to go to the to the
Christian quarter and see, you know, the
Greek Orthodox Church, the Coptic
Orthodox Church, and everything that the
that the the Christian quarter has to
offer in Cairo.
You know, I've been to Sharm el-Sheikh.
I've been to Dahab. I've been to St.
Catherine's Monastery. I climbed to the
very top of of Mount Sinai.
Um
it's an incredible place.
Just absolutely incredible, and I can't
wait to go back. I've I've already taken
my two oldest sons there. Now my third
is going to be is going to be
um
a traveler to Egypt, and uh
he has the travel bug as much as I do.
Yeah, that I look forward to very much.
And thank you for your kindness. I look
forward to meeting you in Philadelphia.
Well, ladies and gents, that's all we
have time for today. I want to thank you
again for your great questions, deep
insightful questions. Thanks for the
conversation. Thank you also for
watching, for liking, for subscribing,
for sharing, and for telling your
friends and family. Again, we're up over
200,000 subscribers.